Indoor cat. Outdoor adventure.
The Garfield Movie is a family, comedy, adventure film directed by Mark Dindal.
Garfield, the world-famous, Monday-hating, lasagna-loving indoor
cat, is about to have a wild outdoor adventure!
After an unexpected reunion with his long-lost father – scruffy street cat Vic – Garfield and his canine friend Odie
are forced from their perfectly pampered life into joining Vic in a hilarious, high-stakes heist.
Garfield (voice), played by Chris Pratt.
Vic (voice), played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Jinx (voice), played by Hannah Waddingham.
Otto (voice), played by Ving Rhames.
Jon (voice), played by Nicholas Hoult.
Marge Malone (voice), played by Cecily Strong.
The Garfield Movie is a 2024 American animated adventure comedy film
based on the comic strip Garfield created by Jim Davis.
Directed by Mark Dindal and written by Paul A.
Kaplan, Mark Torgove, and David Reynolds, it is the third
theatrical Garfield film adaptation and the sixth overall.
The film features the voices of Chris Pratt as Garfield and Samuel L.
Jackson as his father, alongside Hannah Waddingham, Ving Rhames, Nicholas Hoult, Cecily
Strong, Harvey Guillén, Brett Goldstein, Bowen Yang, and Snoop Dogg.
In the film, Garfield is reunited with his long-lost father, a street cat named
Vic, before being forced into joining him on a high-stakes adventure.
Development on The Garfield Movie began at Alcon Entertainment in 2016.
Dindal was announced as the film's director in November 2018,
and pre-production began the following month.
By 2021, Pratt had been cast as Garfield, with the rest
of the cast joining the following year.
The film was animated by DNEG Animation, while John Debney, a
frequent collaborator of Dindal, composed the score.
The Garfield Movie was released internationally on May
1, 2024, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
In the United States, the film premiered at the Grauman's Chinese
Theatre in Los Angeles on May 19, and was released on May 24.
The film received negative reviews from critics and was a box-office
success, grossing $257 million against a $60 million budget.
It was nominated at the 2024 Kids' Choice Awards for Favorite Animated Movie.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of friendship, cat, villain, based on comic, lasagna.
The tone is lighthearted.